<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Much Ado About Everything</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Much Ado About Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 21:48:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Know It When You See It: Knowing Without Knowing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/youknowitwhenyouseeit/youknowitwhenyouseeit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 21:48:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/youknowitwhenyouseeit/youknowitwhenyouseeit/</guid>
      <description>An Example (Recall): You are at a bar with some friends. You are talking about movies and you&amp;rsquo;re trying to remember that one movie from the 1960s about a court case. You feel like you really know it, but you just can&amp;rsquo;t find it in your head. You are also struggling to recall characters and other ways to signal to others what movie you are seaching for. You snap your fingers, look up the the ceiling, let out some &amp;ldquo;umms and ahhs&amp;rdquo; as you feel yourself getting frustrated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Injury?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/injury/injury/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 09:29:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/injury/injury/</guid>
      <description>What is Injury? </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models and The Utility of Personas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/llm-personas/llm-personas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 17:35:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/llm-personas/llm-personas/</guid>
      <description>Some Background Large Language Models like ChatGPT, Claude and Google Bard share a common persona, that of an AI Assistant. They all act as friendly, helpful, sensitive, human aligned chatbots.
Let&amp;rsquo;s prompt two AI chat applications to ask who they are. You&amp;rsquo;ll see we get surprisingly similar responses.
ChatGPT 3.5&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to assist with a wide range of tasks
Anthropic Claude is an assistant that is helpful harmless and honest</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Correctness Trap: How Overreliance on Systems Can Mislead From Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/correctness-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 17:35:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/correctness-truth/</guid>
      <description>Correct vs. True? What is the difference between something correct and something true? Is correctness the same as truthfulness? In other words, are all instances of correctness identical with truthfulness?
Correctness-Truth Alignment
For a Proposition P, where P is correct, P must also be true
At first glance, it seems like they must be. For example, consider a math test. On the test, if you solve an equation, you will be marked as correct.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patterns &amp; Theories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:03:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The world is made of events and like any assortment of data points there can be patterns found. With these patterns we tend to find the story which underlies them, which makes sense of them. These patterns often help us predict the future, solve problems, and are sometimes just pleasing see. What can a deep dive on the concept of patterns reveal about their nature?
1. What is the form of a pattern?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
